Peter Hurd and Henriette Wyeth Hurd
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Peter Hurd and Henriette Wyeth Hurd papers
1917-1989
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Peter Hurd and Henriette Wyeth Hurd
4.0 linear feet
The papers of painters Peter Hurd and Henriette Wyeth Hurd measure 4.0 linear feet, date from 1917 to 1989, and present an overview of their careers and their lives together through correspondence, notes, writings, artwork, printed material, and photographs.
Biographical Note
Peter Hurd was born in 1904 in Roswell, New Mexico, after his parents' move there from the East Coast. He was appointed to the U. S. Military Academy at West Point in 1921, but left two years later to begin an artistic career. After attending Haverford College, he studied under N. C. Wyeth and at the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts from 1924 to 1926. In 1929, he married Wyeth's eldest child, Henriette, who was also a painter.
Henriette Wyeth was born in 1907 in Chadds Ford, Pennsylvania, and studied at the Normal Art School in Boston in 1920, and later at the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts.
During the mid-1930s they settled permanently in San Patricio, New Mexico. Hurd printed lithographs and painted portraits and landscapes in addition to federally-sponsored murals in post offices. Henriette was primarily known as a portrait painter.
Peter Hurd died in 1984.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of painters Peter Hurd and Henriette Wyeth Hurd date from 1917 to 1989 and present an overview of their careers and their lives together. Writer and longtime family friend Paul Horgan, author of Peter Hurd: A Portrait Sketch from Life (Austin: University of Texas Press, 1965), also figures prominently in the collection.
Correspondence forms the bulk of the collection and includes letters to family members, letters to and from Paul Horgan, and Peter Hurd's business correspondence. The collection also includes biographical material such as sketches of family members and genealogy information; miscellaneous notes; scattered writings by Paul Horgan; three drawings by Peter Hurd and a drawing by Paul Horgan; printed material including exhibition catalogs, press releases, and brochures; and two photographs of Paul Horgan. See "Separated Material" for information about the 1999 addition.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into seven series. Material in each series is arranged chronologically, unless otherwise noted.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1980-1984, undated (box 1, 1 folder)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1917-1989 (boxes 1-4, 3.5 linear ft.)
Series 3: Notes, undated (box 4, 1 folder)
Series 4: Writings, 1980-1985 (box 4, 12 folders)
Series 5: Artwork, 1940, undated (box 4, 2 folders)
Series 6: Printed Material, 1928-1929 (box 4, 14 folders)
Series 7: Photographs, 1977, undated (box 4, 1 folder)
Related Material
Related material in the Archives of American Art includes Peter Hurd papers relating to the Section of Fine Arts, 1936-1951. These papers contain correspondence concerning Treasury Department art programs, including miscellaneous papers and printed material concerning Hurd's murals for the Section of Fine Arts in Texas and New Mexico.
Also found in the Archives of American Art is 1 sound tape reel of a transcribed interview with Peter Hurd conducted by Sylvia Loomis, March 28, 1964.
Separated Material
In 1999 the Archives of American Art received an addition to the Peter Hurd and Henriette Wyeth Hurd papers consisting of material concerning Henriette Wyeth Hurd, including an address book; letters regarding portrait commissions, exhibitions, the film The Wyeths: A Father and His Family (Smithsonian World, 1986), and honors and awards; correspondence with Portraits, Inc., 1946-1949, regarding sales and inquiries; letters from Paul Horgan (signed "Plito"); letters from Henriette's father, N.C. Wyeth, and sister, Carolyn Wyeth; more than thirty letters to Andrew Wyeth and his sister Betsy; and several letters from Andrew Wyeth.
Appendix: Complete List of Correspondents from Series 2:3
Abell-Hanger Foundation, 1969-1970
Abilene Club, 1950
Abilene Fine Arts Museum, 1973-1974
Abrams: Harry N. Abrams, Inc., 1963-1971
Abrums, Mrs. John Denise, 1973
Academy Foundation, 1955-1971
Accademia Culturale Adriatica d'Italia, 1949
Achenbach, Col. H. F., 1967
Acosta, Manuel G., 1961-1971
Addison Gallery of American Art, 1968-1969
Addison-Wesley Publishing Company, 1968
Adkins, Eugene B., 1965-1975
Admirals Club, 1962-1972
Ainsworth, Mrs. Ed, 1967-1969
Air Force: see Academy Foundation; see Headquarters [U. S. Air Force] see Headquarters of Fifteenth Air Force
Albert, Harry B., 1954-1969
Albuquerque National Bank, 1963-1969
Alexander, George W., 1974
Alford, J. R. T., 1971
Allen, David, 1967-1968
Allen, Douglas, 1971-1972
Allen, Evelyn, 1967
Aller, Robert, 1974
Alley Book Stall, 1951-1968
Allred, Dr. E. C., 1974
Amarillo Art Center, 1973-1974
Amarillo Public Schools, 1951
America The Beautiful Fund, 1965-1973
American Artist, 1962-1974
American Artists Group, Inc., 1937-1946
American Association of Museums, 1969
American Broadcasting Company, 1966
American Embassy in Mexico, 1965-1966
American Factors, Limited: see AMFAC
American Federation of Arts, 1938-1947
American Heritage, 1964-1975
American Institute of Architects, 1959
American Medical Association, 1965
American Museum of Natural History, 1969-1970
American Orchid Society, Inc., 1951
American Watercolor Society, 1962-1973
AMFAC (American Factors, Ltd.), 1949-1969
Amick, L. D., 1960
Anderman, George G., 1970-1971
Anderson, Clinton P., 1941-1971
Anderson, Donald B., 1962-1967
Anderson, Donald James, undated
Anderson, Mildred K., 1968
Anderson, Robert O., 1954-1972
Andrews/Nelson/Whitehead, Inc., 1964
Annala, Ronald, 1969
Annenberg, Walter H., 1967-1973
Architectural Digest, 1973
Arizona: see Babbitt, Bruce
Arizona Bank, 1973
Arizona Highways, 1952-1974
Arizona State Fair, 1954
Arizona State University, 1965
Armstrong, 1963
Artesia: College of Artesia, 1967-1971
Arthur, Zinn, 1954
Art in America, 1963
Art Institute of Chicago, 1935-1941
Artists Equity Association, Inc., 1965-1974
Artists Showroom, 1973
Artists/USA, Inc., 1970
Ash, Frances and Bob, 1969
Asia Foundation, 1959
Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1962-1974
Associated American Artists, 1936-1975
Aston, Rogers, 1972-1973
Atlantic Monthly Press, 1955-1968
Atwood, Bob, 1967
Austin, Flavius, 1973-1974
Ayer: N. W. Ayer & Son, Inc., 1942-1950
Ayers, Thomas G., 1972-1973
Aylward, Nell, undated
Babbitt, Bruce, 1982
Bacon, Ernst, 1965-1969
Bailey, Kenneth, 1967-1974
Bailey, William S., 1963-1968
Baker Company, 1969
Baker, Frederick, 1970
Baker, Straus, 1964-1968
Bales, Bob, 1962-1966
Balis, C. Wanton, 1950-1951
Ball, Eve, 1966
Ball, Ralph, 1974
Ball, Robert L., 1947
Ballantine, Bill, 1969
Ballin, Hugo, 1937
Barbee Welding Supply Co., 1984
Barnard, Jacqueline, 1968
Barnes, Courtlandt D., 1968-1969
Barnes, Katrina M., undated
Barnes, W. U., 1966-1968
Barry, Claude and Dana, 1974
Bass, Perry, R., 1958-1978
Bates, Jack, 1951-
Beal, Carlton, 1968-1970
Beam: Jim Beam Bottle Project, 1969-1970
Beitz, Lester, 1946
Bell, Carol Ann, 1967
Bencsik Gallery, 1974
Bennett, Fred, 1967
Berger, Tom, 1974
Bergman, B., 1970
Betancourt, Romulo, 1964-1967
Biddle, Francis, 1966
Biddle, John H., 1971
Biggs, John, 1937-1981
Bishop, John, 1950-1951
Bishop Printing & Litho Co., 1971
Bissell, Mrs. Alfred, undated
Black, D. Eric, 1969
Black, Vance, 1972
Blair Galleries, 1966-1970
Blake, Dorothy, undated
Blakenship, W. B., 1968-1969
Blaustein, Julian, 1957-1958
Blue Lake Project, 1969-1972
Blumenstock, Mrs. George, 1972
Bockius, R. W., 1967
Bogle, Dorothy, 1951-1966
Bohemian Club, 1967-1969
Boise Art Association, 1964
Bolt, Reggie, 1966
Bonfoey, Kay, 1973
Bonney, Cecil, 1965
Bonney, William, 1976
Book of the Month Club, Inc., 1971-1972
Book Stall, 1969
Boren, James, 1968
Borton, Hugh, 1970-1980
Bouldin, Marshall, 1968
Bowden, A. J., 1971
Bowers: Charles W. Bowers Memorial Museum, 1964-1965
Bowlin's Mesilla Book Center, 1967
Bowman, Frank, 1950-1963
Bradford, Dewey C., 1961-1965
Bradley, Palmer, 1965
Branch, Hampton, 1964
Brandywine Galleries, Ltd., 1970-1973
Brandywine River Museum, 1979
Branham, Mary, 1961
Brantley, Alexandra, 1974
Brass Door Galleries, 1974
Breck, Louis W., 1960-1965
Breese, E. W., 1967
Breidster, W. Fritz, 1967
Brenton, Daniel, 1969
Brewer, Mike, 1961
Brice, Charles R., 1956
Briggs, James, 1961
Briggs, Randall W., 1960-1974
British Broadcasting Corp., 1942
Brook, A., 1965
Brown, Arthur, 1964
Brown, John F., 1969-1970
Brown, Raymond, 1969
Browne, Mrs. Spencer, 1961
Browser's Magazine, 1972
Brusher, Hal, 1973
Buckingham, L. J., 1969
Bunting, Mrs. Frederick W., 1965-1966
Bureau of Reclamation, 1969-1974
Burgess, Ryk, 1971
Burnham, Alice, 1971
Burress, Mary, 1972
Busch, Niven, 1946-1973
Business Men's Assurance, 1962-1972
Butcher, Mrs. Cary P., 1964-1965
Butler, Charles, 1969
Butler Institute of American Art, 1967
Butoler, Olivia, undated
Bynner, Witter, 1940-1975
Byrom, Gilliam, 1973
Cabell, Charles P., 1953-1967
California Institute of the Arts: see Bales, Bob
Carlin Galleries, 1981
Carroll, John M., 1969-1971
Carter, Jimmy, undated envelope fragment
Chester Art Guild: see Dawson, James
Chicago: see Art Institute of Chicago
Circle Gallery, Ltd., 1972-1974
Coe Kerr Gallery, Inc.: see Busch, Niven
Colorado: University of Colorado, undated
Copley, James S., 1967-1973
Cosmos Club, 1960-1967
Country Gentleman, 1941-1952
Coward-McCann, Inc., 1944-1957
Craver Farms, 1982
Daeuble: Carroll, Daeuble, Du Sang and Rand, 1967
Dahl, Bjarne B., 1973
Dailey, Fred, 1972
Dakota Artists Guild, 1969
Dale, Mrs. Chester, 1966
Dall Smith, Inc., 1963-1967
Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, 1937-1960
Dallas Terminal Annex, 1938-1978
Dalrymple, Mrs. Glen, 1965
Daniels, Charles E., undated
Darlington, Carol S., 1964
Darlington, Jack, 1967
Darnell, Casey and Blair, 1965
Dartmouth College, 1960-1961
Datsun endorsement, 1972-1979
Daughtery, Frank, 1959
Davenport, Mrs. O. H., undated
Davey, Danny, 1969-1971
Davidson, Barbara, 1968-1969
Davidson, Harry M., 1967
Davis, John, 1956
Davis, Larry, 1967-1968
Davis, Morgan J., 1961-1969
Davis, Mrs. Ray V., 1954-1966
Davis, W. B., 1967
Dawley, David G., 1967
Dawson, James, 1970
Day, Fred, 1951
Dean, Susan, 1965-1967
Deane, Martha, 1968
Decorators' Showcase, 1967
Deere & Company, 1972
Delaware: University of Delaware, 1978
Dena, Benito Palomino, 1967-1970
Denkhoff, Ray, 1967
Denman, Franklin & Denman, 1967
Dent: J. M. Dent & Sons, 1965
Dent, Mrs. John, 1966
Desert Magazine, undated
Desert Magazine Art Gallery, 1962-1963
Dietz, Mrs. Robert, 1965
Diggdon, Philip D., 1974
Dillon, Austin, H., 1969-1971
Dixon, Don, 1968
Dixon, George, 1959
Dobie-Paisano Project, 1965-1966
Dobson, B. C., 1967
Dodds, R. W., 1949
Dohanos, Stevan, 1963
Dolan, Eugene, 1969
Donald Art Company, Inc., 1964
Donti, Jerrold, 1968
Doornbos, E., 1966
Dougherty, Dudley T., 1967
Douglas Art Association, 1972
Dow, James, 1961-1968
Dow: Louis F. Dow Co., 1955-1956
Drake, Blaine, 1963-1967
Drankow, Mrs. Matty, 1966
Dressel & Altman, 1967
Driskell, Mrs. Joseph, 1967-1968
Dunn, Fern, 1968
Dunn, Helen, 1967
Dupre, Grace D., 1965-1972
Dysart, Cabot, 1963-1967
Easter, Sister Claretta, 1966-1967
Easterling, Ross, 1969
Eastern New Mexico University, 1963-1979
Eastern Washington State Historical Society, 1964
East Texas State University, 1961-1970
Eaton, Bonnie, 1968
Eaton, L.?, 1952
Eaton, Nan and Bob, 1965-1970
Eckman, Mary, 1966
Edinburgh Regional College, 1951-1952
Editions Press, 1973
Edwards, J. W., 1969
Egri, Ted, 1959
Ehrt, Herbert A., 1951
Eiseman, Douglass W., 1961
Eisenhower, Julie: see Nixon, Pat
Eisenstaedt, Alfred, 1968
Eliot, Alexander, 1970
Elliott, Ben, 1965
Elliott, George, 1951-1972
Elliott, Hazel, 1967
Elliott, Will, 1941
Elliston, Lura Duff, undated
Elms Gallery, 1964
El Paso Museum of Art, 1961-1978
Embry, W. Glenn, 1953-1966
Emmet, Barton, 1965-1966
Emmet, John, 1966-1967
Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1944-1977
English, Frances Bonnell, 1969
Ericson, Andrea, undated
Espinoza, Noel, 1969
Esty: William Esty Company, 1962
Evans, Annie Mae, 1962
Evans, Dorothy T., 1965-1973
Evans, Elinor, 1972
Evans, Ernestine, 1968
Evans, G. W., 1960-1961
Evans, Ira K., undated
Evans, Joe M., undated
Evans, Louise, 1955-1967
Evans, Truett, 1962-1970
Ewbank, H. R., 1954
Ezell, James Kerry, 1970
Fairbanks, Mrs. Douglas, 1971
Falkner, Mrs. Herbert, 1970
Fall, Hugh V., 1936
Faltermeier, Robert, 1973
Family Circle Magazine, 1954
Farm Journal, 1950-1970
Farnsworth Television & Radio Corp., 1942-1948
Farr, R., 1965
Farrar & Rinehart, 1940
Farrington, Mrs. L. H., 1946
Faude, Susan, 1967-1968
Faudree, William, 1977
Fauntleroy, O. W., 1959-1960
Faver, Robert M., 1974-1975
Feather, G. A., 1951
Fedway [Department Store], 1965
Feist, Herbert E., 1971
Felpes, undated
Ferargil, Inc., 1950
Ferguson, Tana, undated
Ferguson, Thomas, 1967
Fergusson, Erna, 1951
Ferroni, Brimo, 1947
Ferrucci, Mario, 1968
Fideler Company, 1952
Field Enterprises Corp., 1965-1975
Fielding, William, 1967
Film Enterprises, 1972-1973
Fine Arts Commission, 1959-1962
Finley, David Edward, 1965-1969
Fireman's Fund, 1967
First National Bank of Albuquerque, 1970
First National Bank of Chicago, 1962-1974
Flannery, Vaughan, undated
Flannery, W. E., 1954
Fleetwood, Charles, 1969
Fleischmann, Justin and Lillian, 1966-1971
Fleming, Joseph, 1970
Fleming, Pat, 1968
Flynn, J. Walter, 1960-1966
Fogg Art Museum, 1940-1971
Foote, Cone, & Belding, 1949-1955
Ford, Jesse Hill, 1965
Ford Motor Company, 1950-1969
Ford, Merrill, 1965-1968
Fort, Tomlinson, 1961-1973
Fortune, Cedric, 1973
Foster, Mrs. Maurice, 1969
Foster, Robert, 1971-1973
Foust, Chester, 1955-1961
Fowler, Frank N., 1973-1974
Fox, Chris, 1966-1967
Francis, Helen, 1974
Frank, Paul A., 1946
Franklin Mint, 1970-1973
Franklin Pierce College, 1968
Frauwirth, Sidney, 1964-1965
Friedberg, Opal, 1967
Friends Magazine, 1962-1964
Frison, Don, 1969-1970
Fuller, Charles D., 1968
Fulton, R. H., 1969
Fundingsland, Mrs. S. E., 1974
Georgia: University of Georgia, 1980
Goddard, Robert H., 1964-1971
Golden Anniversary Friendship Flight, 1962
Grant, W. D.: see Business Men's Assurance
Guelph: University of Guelph (Ontario, Canada), 1977
Hacker, George, 1951
Hackley Art Gallery, 1949-1954
Hadley, John M., 1970
Haeberle, Peter, 1970-1971
Hagberg, Peter, 1967
Hagerman First National Bank, 1962
Hale, Mrs. D. L., 1978
Hall Brothers, Inc., 1951
Hall, Walter B., 1969
Halliburton, Erle, 1968
Hallmark Cards, Inc., 1949-1962
Halsey, Admiral, 1945 (letter signed by secretary)
Halteman, Theodore, 1968
Hamilton, Donald W., 1969-1970
Hamilton, Jim, 1970
Hamilton, John, 1966
Hamilton, Minard, 1961
Hammer Galleries, 1962
Hammer, Mrs., 1964
Hamner, Laura, 1939-1965
Hanna, Mrs. Dan R., 1966
Hanrahan, James S., 1961
Hanes, Mabel, 1964
Hardcastle: George Hardcastle and Son, Inc., 1962
Hardy, Gladys E., 1970
Harman, Fred, 1969
Harmon, H. R., 1955-1956
Harper, Mrs. Gerald, 1973
Harris, Mrs. Charles Lee, 1971
Harris, Mrs. Henry B., 1975
Harris, W. T., 1965-1968
Harrison, John R., 1966-1970
Harrison, Milton, 1964-1967
Harvard Art Review, 1969
Haswell, Anthony, 1964
Hatch, Francis W., 1967-1970
Hathaway, C., 1966
Haverford College, 1951-1981
Hawkins, Gardiner, 1972-1974
Hawkins, H. H., 1967
Hawks, John, 1967
Haynsworth, Mrs. R. F., 1971
Headquarters [U. S. Air Force], 1942-1976
Headquarters of Fifteenth Air Force, 1955-1966
Healey, Giles Greville, 1964
Heard, John F., 1965
Heart Association of Broward County, 1966-1969
Heath, Robert and Jean, 1976-1980
Heckman: W. L. Heckman Co., 1967
Heineman, Ben W., 1966-1976
Helbis, John and Shirley, 1966
Hemmle, Agnes and Gene, 1967
Henderson, undated
Henderson, Charles, 1950-1965
Hensley, Gene, 1970
Hensley, Jackson, 1967-1968
Hercules Powder Company, 1953-1974
Hergesheimer, Joseph, 1925-1941
Heron, Clyde, 1969
Herrin, Lex, 1967
Heston, Loomis, 1969-1970
Hettinger: H. I. Hettinger & Co., 1953
Hevenor, Richard K., 1969
Heyser, Estill S., 1950
Heywood, Barrett H., 1975
Hickman, Charles S., 1973
High Mesa College, 1968
Hightower, Frank, 1971
Hildebrand, Ira, 1967-1971
Hilliard, H. T., 1966-1969
Hinkle, Clarence E., 1959-1972
Hirsch, Peter, 1966
Hirschi & Adler, 1967-1968
Hissom, R. J. 1967-1971
Hitch, Henry C., 1968-1970
Hoard, Mary C., 1973-1974
Hodson, R. J., 1968
Hoffer, Clarence W., 1961
Hogg, Eleanor H., 1963
Hogsett, Glade C., 1959
Holden, W. Curry, 1950-1977
Holle, Charles G., 1968-1969
Holliday: W. J. Holliday & co., 1951
Hollister, Paul, 1971
Holman, Herschel E., 1960
Holmes, Myrtle, 1972
Holt: Henry Holt and Company, Inc., 1956
Holt, Robert B., 1968-1971
Homer, Jack, 1951
Hondo Valley Traffic Safety, 1963
Honolulu Art Association, 1971
Hoopes, Clement R., 1971
Hoover, Mrs. Thomas B., 1964
Hopwell, Mrs., undated
Hopwood, Mrs. W. J., 1975
Horgan, Ed, 1950-
Horwitz, Mary Lou, undated
Horgan, Paul: see Correspondence, Letters to and from Paul Horgan
Hosford, Penny, 1965
Hotton, Esther H., 1964-1965
Houghton Mifflin Company, 1943-1972
House & Garden, 1955-1975
Houston Chronicle, 1966
Houston Post, 1954
Howard, Eldon B., 1967-1968
Howard Roy, 1963
Hubbard, Jere, 1967-1968
Hughes, Ruth, 1972
Huling, Ray G., 1974
Hulse, Max D., 1968-1970
Humble Oil & Refining Company, 1955-1961
Hunsaker, Joe Ben, 1968
Hunt, Robert N., 1948
Hunter Gallery, 1969
Hunter, Pamela, 1972
Hurley, Norma, 1971
Hurley, Wilson D., 1968
Hutchins, Susan, 1923-1928
Interior: Department of the Interior: see Bureau of Reclamation
MacNider, Jack, 1972
McKee, John J., 1971-1982
Mesilla Design Center: see Bowlin
Mexico: see American Embassy in Mexico
National Academy of Design, 1982-1989
New Mexico: Office of the Governor, 1981
New Mexico State University: see Anderson, Clinton P.
New Mexico: University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, 1975-1978
Nixon, Pat, 1978-1980
Oklahoma: University of Oklahoma Press, 1975-1977
Quivira Bookshop: see Dietz, Mrs. Robert
Rainier: Prince Rainier of Monaco, 1976
Reagan, President and Mrs., 1981 and 1984 (Christmas cards designed by Jamie Wyeth)
Rockefeller, Mrs. John D., III, 1978
Rummell, Mrs. W. B., 1983
St. John's College, 1963-1977
St. Vincent Hospital, 1979
Schumpert, Billy, 1968
Scripps College, 1977
Smithsonian Institution, 1978
Suzette International, 1981
Swallow Press, Inc., 1969-1977
Tankersley, Mrs. Garvin, 1975-1978
Taylor, Robert, 1976
Texaco, 1977-1982
Texas A&M University, 1980-1982
Texas Centennial Exposition, 1936
Texas-New Mexico Library Association, 1976-1977
Texas: University of Texas, Austin, 1964-1979
Thompson, Daniel V., 1975
Treidel, Mrs. Walter, 1974-1975
Trigg, Mrs., undated
Twaddell, Kristie, 1975
United States Information Agency, 1975-1976
Vance, Mrs, Alex, 1975-1978
Vance, “Monk”, 1975
Vinson, Bailie, 1959-1978
Vollum, Orville, 1973-1975
Wagley, Philip F., 1977
Walbridge, Norton S., 1976
Walker Air Force Base, 1954-1967
Walters, Richard H., 1975
Waltrip, Rufus, 1972
Watson-Guptill Publications, 1969-1975
Watson, Jo Ann, 1974-1975
Waxman, Lilo, undated
Webster, Jack, 1976-1980
Weitzenhoffer, Mrs. Aaron M., 1976
West, W. F., 1979
Western Fine Arts Foundation, 1974-1977
Whetstone Fine Framing, 1980
Wiggins, Walt, 1978
Wilkerson, Tom, 1975-1977
Wilkinson, Kirk C., 1979
Willis, Ken, 1978-1979
Willner, Catherine, 1979
Wilmington Savings Fund, 1973-1975
Wilmot, Paul D., 1977
Wilson: Sandra Wilson Galleries, 1977
Wilson: Woodrow Wilson Fine Arts, 1980
Wood, Dennis, 1975
Woods, Carol R., 1980
Woodsmall, Warren O., 1976
Woodson, Weldon D., 1977
Woodward, Daniel E., 1975
Woodworth, Charlie H., 1978
Woolfitt, Adam, 1969
Woolley, Bennett L., 1972
Woolvin, Sam, 1976
Wyeth, Betsy, 1976
Wyeth: Nicholas Wyeth, Inc., 1978
Wyoming: University of Wyoming, 1976
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following index terms. People, families and organizations are listed under "Names" when they are creators or contributors and under "Subjects" when they are the topic of collection contents.
Subjects:
Horgan, Paul, 1903- -- Photographs; Nixon, Pat, 1912- -- Photographs
Subjects-Topical:
Women painters -- New Mexico; Painters -- New Mexico; Portrait painters -- New Mexico
Types of Materials:
Drawings; Photographs
Names:
Annenberg, Walter H., 1908-; Eisenhower, Julie Nixon; Eisenstaedt, Alfred; Horgan, Paul, 1903-; Nixon, Pat, 1912-; Wyeth, Henriette, 1907-; Wyeth, N. C. (Newell Convers), 1882-1945
Provenance
The Peter Hurd and Henriette Wyeth Hurd papers were donated to the Archives of American Art in 1991 and 1994 by Michael Hurd and Henriette Wyeth Hurd, the son and widow of Peter Hurd.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Patrons must use microfilm copy.
Alternative Forms Available
With the exception of the 1999 addition (which is unfilmed), the collection is available on microfilm reels 5125-5129. The microfilm is available for interlibrary loan. Use of the 1999 addition requires an appointment and is limited to the Washington D.C. research facility.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1980-1984, undated, Series 1:; (box 1, 1 folder)
  Biographical material includes a 1984 Wyeth family tree chart, undated biographical sketches of family members, and a 1982 report of Henriette Wyeth's medical history.
  - Biographical Material, 1980-1984, undated (Box 1, Reel 5125)
- Correspondence, 1917-1989, undated, Series 2:; (boxes 1-4, 3.5 linear ft.)
  Correspondence includes letters to family members; letters to and from Paul Horgan; and Peter Hurd's business correspondence. Letters to and from Horgan lack a direct exchange of letters, necessitating their description as letters rather than correspondence.
  Thirty of the letters from Paul Horgan, and several others, are photocopies. Ten letters are in Spanish.
  Arrangement of this series reflects the original arrangement of the creators: personal letters to family members and to Paul Horgan are arranged chronologically, while Peter Hurd's business correspondence is arranged alphabetically. The series is arranged into three sub-series.
  2.1: Letters to Family Members, 1917-1978
  2.2: Letters to and from Paul Horgan, 1927-1988, undated
  2.3: Business Correspondence of Peter Hurd, 1923-1989, undated
  - Letters to Family Members, 1917-1978, 2.1:
    Letters are to Wyeth famiy members, primarily Carolyn and N.C. Wyeth.
    - Letters to Family Members, 1917-1978, (68 folders) (Box 1, Reel 5125)
  - Letters to and from Paul Horgan, 1927-1988, undated, 2.2:
    - Letters to and from Paul Horgan, 1927-1988, undated, (25 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5125-5126)
  - Business Correspondence of Peter Hurd, 1923-1989, undated, 2.3:
    This subseries includes letters from Walter Annenberg, Julie Eisenhower, Alfred Eisenstaedt, Mrs. Douglas Fairbanks, and Prince Ranier of Monaco. Six letters from Pat Nixon include photographs of Henriette Wyeth Hurd finishing Mrs. Nixon's portrait.
    Folders are arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Some of the folders contain letters from a single correspondent and some contain letters from a range of correspondents, all or whom are not listed in the folder title. A complete list of correspondents supplements the container list below and can be found in the Appendix.
    - Abell-Hanger Foundation - Abilene Fine Arts Museum (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Abrams: Harry N. Abrams, Inc., 1963-1971 (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Abrums, Mrs. John Denise, 1973 (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Academy Foundation, 1955-1971 (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Accademia Culturale Adriatica d'Italia - Achenbach, Col. H. F. (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Acosta, Manuel G., 1961-1971 (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Addison Gallery of American Art - Adkins, Eugene B. (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Admirals Club, 1962-1972 (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Ainsworth, Mrs. Ed - Alexander, George W. (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Alford, J. R. T. - Aller, Robert (Box 2, Reel 5126)
    - Alley Book Stall, 1951-1968 (Box 2, Reel 5126)